toolbarn.com 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Toolbarn.com

Revised: January 8th, 2018

INTRODUCTION

Northecomm LLC (“we” or “us” or “our”) respects the privacy of our users (“user” or “you”). This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard your information when you visit our website, Toolbarn.com. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect:

This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect:

  * On this Site.
  * In email, text, and other electronic messages between you and this Site.
  * Through mobile and desktop applications downloaded from, or connected to, this Site, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and this Site. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by:

  * Us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by us or any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries).
  * Any third party, including through any application or content that may link to or be accessible from or on the Site.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. BY ACCESSING OR USING THIS SITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT ACCESS THE SITE.

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason.  We will alert you about any changes by updating the “Revised” date shown at the top of this Privacy Policy.  Any changes or modifications will be effective immediately upon posting the updated Privacy Policy on the Site, and you waive the right to receive specific notice of each such change or modification. You are encouraged to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed of updates. You will be deemed to have been made aware of, will be subject to, and will be deemed to have accepted the changes in any revised Privacy Policy by your continued use of the Site after the date such revised Privacy Policy is posted.

INFORMATION WE COLLECT

The information we may collect on the Site includes: 

##### Personal Information

Personally identifiable information, such as your name, shipping address, email address, and telephone number, and demographic information, such as your age, gender, hometown, and interests (“personal information”).

##### Payment Information

Payment information, such as data related to your payment method (e.g. valid credit card number, card brand, expiration date) that we may collect when you purchase, order, return, exchange our products, or request information about our services from the Site.

##### Other Information

Information about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access the Site, and usage details, including IP address, browser type, operating system, access times, and the pages you viewed directly before and after accessing the Site.

HOW WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATION

We collect the foregoing information:

  * When you provide it to us.
  * Automatically as you navigate the Site.

##### Information You Provide to Us

We collect information you provide directly to us, for example, when you create an account, participate in interactive features of the Site (such as online chat or message boards), fill out a form, respond to a survey, request customer support, or otherwise communicated with us via the Site.  Such information may include personal information, payment information, and any other information you choose to provide.

##### Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Site

When you access or use the Site, we automatically collect information about you, including the following:

  * We log information about your use of the Site, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, and the page you visited before and after navigating to the Site.
  * We use various technologies to collect information, including sending cookies to your computer or mobile device and placing web beacons on pages of the Site. 
    * Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us to improve the Site and your experience, see which areas and features of the Site are popular, and count visits. Most browsers are set to accept cookies by default.
    * Web beacons are small electronic files (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages and for other related Site statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain Site content and verifying system and server integrity).
  * We may also partner with selected third-party vendors, such as Google Analytics, to allow tracking technologies and remarketing services on the Site through the use of first party cookies and third-party cookies to, among other things, analyze and track users’ use of the Site, determine the popularity of certain content, and better understand online activity. By accessing the Site, you consent to the collection and use of your information by these third-party vendors. You are encouraged to review their respective privacy policies and contact them directly for responses to your questions. We do not transfer personal information to these third-party vendors. However, If you do not want any information to be collected and used by tracking technologies, you can visit the third-party vendor’s website or Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out Tool or Digital Advertising Alliance Opt-Out Tool.

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

Having accurate information about you permits us to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience.  Specifically, we may use information collected about you via the Site to:

  * Assist law enforcement and respond to subpoenas.
  * Create and manage your account.
  * Deliver targeted advertising, coupons, newsletters, and promotions, and other information regarding the Site and our mobile application to you.
  * Communicate with you regarding your account or order.
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages.
  * Fulfill and manage purchases, orders, payments, and other transactions related to the Site.
  * Generate a personal profile about you to make future visits to the Site more personalized.
  * Increase the efficiency and operation of the Site.
  * Monitor and analyze usage and trends to improve your experience with the Site.
  * Notify you of updates to the Site.
  * Offer new products, services, and/or recommendations to you.
  * Perform other business activities as needed.
  * Prevent fraudulent transactions, monitor against theft, and protect against criminal activity.
  * Process payments and refunds.
  * Request feedback and contact you about your use of the Site.
  * Resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems.
  * Respond to product and customer service requests.
  * Provide, maintain, and improve the Site.
  * Process and deliver contest entries and rewards.
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs and provide you with better service.
  * Fulfill any other purpose for which you provided the information.

DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may share information we have collected about you in certain situations. Your information may be disclosed as follows:

##### By Law or to Protect Rights

If we believe the release of information about you is necessary to respond to legal process, to investigate or remedy potential violations of our policies, or to protect the rights, property, and safety of others, we may share your information as permitted or required by any applicable law, rule, or regulation.  This includes exchanging information with other entities for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

##### Third-Party Service Providers

We may share your information with third parties that perform services for us or on our behalf, including payment processing, data analysis, email delivery, hosting services, customer service, and marketing assistance.  Such third parties are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them.        

##### Affiliates

We may share your information with our affiliates, in which case we will require those affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. Affiliates include our parent company and any subsidiaries, joint venture partners, or other companies that we control or that are under common control with us.

##### Other Third Parties

We may share your information with advertisers and investors for the purpose of conducting general business analysis. We may also share your information with such third parties for marketing purposes, as permitted by law.

##### Sale or Bankruptcy

If we reorganize or sell all or a portion of our assets, undergo a merger, or are acquired by another entity, we may transfer your information to the successor entity.  If we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, your information would be an asset transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that the transferee may decline to honor commitments we make in this Privacy Policy.

THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES

The Site may contain links to third-party websites and applications of interest, including advertisements and external services, that are not affiliated with us. Once you have used these links to leave the Site, any information you provide to these third parties is not covered by this Privacy Policy, and we cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of your information. Before visiting and providing any information to any third-party websites, you should inform yourself of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of the third party responsible for that website, and should take those steps necessary to, in your discretion, protect the privacy of your information. We are not responsible for the content, privacy and security practices, or policies of any third parties, including other websites, services, or applications that may be linked to or from the Site.

SOCIAL SHARING FEATURES

The Site may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools (such as the Facebook “Like” button and the Twitter “Follow” button), which let you share actions you take on the Site with other media.  The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the privacy settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature.

Use these social sharing features at your own risk.  No security measures, including the privacy settings referenced in the paragraph above, are perfect or impenetrable.  We cannot and do not guarantee that the information you share using such features will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.  For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.   

SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION

We use administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your personal information from loss, theft, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction, including Secure Sockets Layer 256-bit encryption. While we have taken reasonable steps to secure the personal information you provide to us, please be aware that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable, and no method of data transmission can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. Any information disclosed online is vulnerable to interception and misuse by unauthorized parties. Therefore, we cannot guarantee complete security if you provide personal information.

We do not retain your information for longer than is necessary for our business purposes.  When we no longer need your information, we dispose of it safely.

POLICY FOR CHILDREN

We do not knowingly solicit information from or market to children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Site or on or through any of its features.  If you become aware of any data we have collected from children under age 13, please contact us using the contact information provided below.  If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. 

CONTROLS FOR DO-NOT-TRACK FEATURES 

Most web browsers and some mobile operating systems include a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) feature or setting you can activate to signal your privacy preference not to have data about your online browsing activities monitored and collected.  No uniform technology standard for recognizing and implementing DNT signals has been finalized. As such, we do not currently respond to DNT browser signals or any other mechanism that automatically communicates your choice not to be tracked online. If a standard for online tracking is adopted that we must follow in the future, we will inform you about that practice in a revised version of this Privacy Policy.   

YOUR CHOICES

##### Account Information

You may at any time review, correct, or delete the information in your account or terminate your account by: 

  * Logging into user account settings and updating the user account.
  * Contacting us using the contact information provided below. 

Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and information from our active databases. However, some information may be retained in our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and/or comply with legal requirements.

##### Emails and Communications

If you no longer wish to receive correspondence, emails, or other communications from us, you may opt-out by:

  * Noting your preferences at the time you register your account with the Site.
  * Logging into your account settings and updating your preferences.
  * Contacting us using the contact information provided below.

If you opt-out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.  If you no longer wish to receive correspondence, emails, or other communications from third parties, you are responsible for contacting those third parties directly.

##### Cookies and Web Beacons

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default.  You can remove or reject cookies, but be aware that such action could affect the availability and functionality of the Site. You may not decline web beacons. However, they can be rendered ineffective by declining all cookies or by modifying your web browser’s settings to notify you each time a cookie is tendered, permitting you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. Be aware that getting a new computer, installing a new browser, upgrading an existing browser, or erasing or otherwise altering your browser’s cookies files may also clear certain opt-out cookies, plug-ins, or settings.

##### Other

You can always choose not to provide information when you are prompted to do so.  Note that if you do not provide us with certain mandatory information, then you may be unable to take advantage of certain features on the Site. 

CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below.

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with the Site, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Site. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include the email address associated with your account and a statement that you reside in California.  We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Site, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems.

CONTACT US

You have the right to access, correct, and delete inaccuracies in your personal information and privacy preferences on the Site at any time by signing into your account and editing your personal information in your account profile.  You may also do so by contacting us via telephone, postal mail, or email.  If at any time you wish to opt-out of our use of your information for internal marketing purposes, or if you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

  * NorthEcomm LLC
  * Toolbarn.com
  * 866-597-3850  8-5P CST
  * Sales@toolbarn.com
  * 300 E Locust St
  * Carter Lake, IA 51510
